Ismail OMODARA

PRODUCT ENGINEER

https://ismailomodara.netlify.app ismailomodara.io@gmail.com

Osun, Nigeria | +234 817 959 1037

ABOUT ME

I'm a Frontend Engineer with 3+ years of experience designing and building web applications, crafting seamless digital experiences. With a background as a UI Designer, I build functional experiences on the web, because I think and see things not just as an engineer, but also as a user.

EXPERIENCE

Feb 2020 - Present | Frontend Engineer - Edenlife Inc

- Currently building a Customer Relationship Management system that monitors, and logs a customer lifecycle usage of the product in real-time.
- · Built and managing dashboard for day-to-day running and management of operations.
- Collaborated with a team to build a customer-facing mobile app.
- Built lead-gen pages for customer acquisition.

Nov 2020 - May 2021 | Product Engineer - NQLB Limited

- Designed, created, and implemented an information-gathering application, with user flow and experience targeted at people with little technological knowledge.
- Designed and implemented an application that allows organizations to verify users based on specific verification methods.
- Designed and implemented the company's website targeted to acquired different audiences.

Feb 2020 - Jun 2020 | Frontend Engineer - Init Africa

- Built and managed an application that enables photographers to manage clients, clients' contracts, schedules, and albums.
- Built a website theme generator that helps a photographer showcase their work.
- Designed product website for customers outreach.
- Pinpointed user experience issues to devise targeted suggestions for creating a cohesive user experience.

Apr 2019 - Sep 2019 | Frontend Engineer - Fundall

- Developed websites targeted at audiences that fit the ideal customer profile for acquisition.
- Built web application to enable web experience for product usage (savings, identify verification, and, loan applications)
- Collaborated with a team to build a mobile app for a savings and loan application platform.

Oct 2018 - Mar 2019 | Frontend Developer Intern - Cregital Digital Agency

- · Collaborated with a team to develop a website builder, enables users with zero-code knowledge to build online portfolios.
- Built an application that helps generate embeddable email signatures.
- Developed and managed websites for clients.

Jun 2018 - Aug 2018 | User Interface Designer - Mettalloids Limited

- Designed interface for a customer acquisition website.
- Designed interface for an application that tracks and displays data for oil tanks in real-time.

SKILLS

Design - Sketch, Adobe XD, Figma, Invision

Tools - VCS, CI/CD

PROJECTS

Jan 2021 - **The Shoppies -** A web-based movie nominations app. https://sm-awards.netlify.app/

May 2020 - **VidPages -** A platform for creating video based events. https://vidrl.netlify.app/

Dec 2020 - FluxChat - A video chat platform. https://flux-chat.netlify.app/

May 2020 - Truemirror - A web-based video call platform. https://truemirror.netlify.app/

Dec 2019 - **CoinsList -** A basic webpage that shows crypto coins and prices. https://coins-list.netlify.app/

Dec 2019 - **TVIO -** A platform that allows users to buy and pay later without a credit card. https://tvio.netlify.app/

Web - Vue, Nuxt, HTML, CSS, SCSS, JavaScript, GraphQL

EDUCATION

Feb 2020 - B.Sc Computer Engineering Obafemi Awowlowo University.

Feb 2021 - React Nanodegree - Udacity